<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tutorial on drpaneas</title>
    <link>https://panosgeorgiadis.com/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tutorial on drpaneas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 15:39:35 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://panosgeorgiadis.com/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to run Traefik ingress controller as non-root</title>
      <link>https://panosgeorgiadis.com/blog/2019/01/16/how-to-run-traefik-ingress-controller-as-non-root/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 15:39:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://panosgeorgiadis.com/blog/2019/01/16/how-to-run-traefik-ingress-controller-as-non-root/</guid>
      <description>What is ingress? Ingress are (in a sense) reverse-proxies. But to understand, you need to know first what a proxy is &amp;ndash; and only then will be able to understand the reverse of it.
What is a proxy? For those of you who do not know what a proxy is, the word proxy describes someone/something acting on behalf of someone/something else. In terms on networking, when we are talking about a proxy server we are talking about one server that is acting on behalf of another server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contribute to minikube in a nutshell</title>
      <link>https://panosgeorgiadis.com/blog/2018/09/28/contribute-to-minikube-in-a-nutshell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 16:29:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://panosgeorgiadis.com/blog/2018/09/28/contribute-to-minikube-in-a-nutshell/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to contribute to minikube (and other similar packages) when the only thing that is needed is just a version bump in the spec file. You first need to install these:
# zypper in osc spec-cleaner Configure your ~/.oscrc file:
[general] no_verify = 1 extra-pkgs = vim less mc [https://api.opensuse.org] user=pgeorgiadis # CHANGE email=pgeorgiadis@suse.com # CHANGE pass=123456789 # CHANGE trusted_prj=SUSE:SLE-12:GA openSUSE:13.2 openSUSE:Leap:42.3 openSUSE:Factory Base:System Virtualization:containers SUSE:SLE-12-SP3:GA SUSE:SLE-12:SLE-Module-Containers SUSE:Templates:Images:SLE-12-SP3:Base SUSE:SLE-12-SP3:Update openSUSE:Leap:42.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My personal Go environment setup</title>
      <link>https://panosgeorgiadis.com/blog/2018/09/27/my-personal-go-environment-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 17:34:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://panosgeorgiadis.com/blog/2018/09/27/my-personal-go-environment-setup/</guid>
      <description>How many go version do you have installed? The default upstream location for the binary is: /usr/local/go. But in SUSE it is: /usr/bin/go. This is a symlink created via update-alternatives.
# update-alternatives --list go /usr/lib64/go/1.10/bin/go /usr/lib64/go/1.8/bin/go /usr/lib64/go/1.9/bin/go I want to keep only the 1.10 so I will remove the others:
# zypper rm $(rpm -qf /usr/lib64/go/1.8/bin/go) $(rpm -qf /usr/lib64/go/1.9/bin/go) To verify, try update-alternatives once more. There should be only one version:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy openSUSE Leap15 VM in Kubernetes using KubeVirt</title>
      <link>https://panosgeorgiadis.com/blog/2018/03/15/deploy-opensuse-leap15-vm-in-kubernetes-using-kubevirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 20:46:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://panosgeorgiadis.com/blog/2018/03/15/deploy-opensuse-leap15-vm-in-kubernetes-using-kubevirt/</guid>
      <description>Introduction If you think that Kubernetes is a cluster for managing containers, then you are dead wrong. Kubernetes is a cluster for managing Pods. In most cases, a Pod is considered to be an abstraction of an container object, so Pod talks to Docker and they know each other. What happens though when we introduce a new guy called libvirt and we learn Pod to talk to it? We have KubeVirt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to start with OpenFaaS</title>
      <link>https://panosgeorgiadis.com/blog/2017/11/08/how-to-start-with-openfaas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 22:08:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://panosgeorgiadis.com/blog/2017/11/08/how-to-start-with-openfaas/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Before we get into what is serverless or openfaas, I would like to talk about the concept behind this. So, before going into the details, I want to give you the big picture of this new way of developing applications and how the users are supposed to use them.
Containers are now more efficient than ever So let’s go back in time, when computers were enormous things and filled complete rooms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Basics</title>
      <link>https://panosgeorgiadis.com/blog/2017/05/08/kubernetes-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 22:08:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://panosgeorgiadis.com/blog/2017/05/08/kubernetes-basics/</guid>
      <description>What is Kubernetes By definition, Kubernetes is an open source container cluster manager, and it is usually referred to by its internal name withing Google development - k8s. Google donated it to the open source world as a &amp;ldquo;seed technology&amp;rdquo; at 2015, to the newly formed CNCF - Cloud Native Computing Foundation, which established partnership with The Linux Foundation. The primary goal of Kubernetes is to provide a platform for automating deployment, scaling and operations of application containers across a cluster of hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
